credible.com 2016-05-20

# Credible® - Refinance Student Loans, Student Loans, Personal Loans

Welcome to Credible.com, the website and online service of Credible Labs Inc. (“Credible,” “we,” or “us”). We are committed to protecting your privacy. Our Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and protect information that applies to our Service, and your choices about the collection and use of your information. 

### How we collect and use information

Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in our Terms of Use. By using the Service, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy and Credible’s Terms of Use. We collect the following types of information about you: 

##### Information you provide us directly

The information we collect from you will vary depending on the product or service requested. We may ask for certain information such as your username, first and last name, birth date, telephone number, email address, college or university, year of graduation, course of study, outstanding loan balances, social security number, income, employment history and other details related to your financial situation when you register for a Credible account, submit an Offer request or if you correspond with us. We may collect information that you voluntarily provide to us when using the Service. 

We may also collect and store information that you provide to us about other people (such as co-signers), including their first and last name, address, telephone number, birth date, email address, and social security number. 

We may also retain any messages you send through the Service, customer service correspondence, and may collect information you provide in User Content you post to the Service. 

We use this information to operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service. This may include customization and tailoring the Service features according to the information that you provide. 

We may directly collect analytics data, or use third party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service. These tools collect information sent by your browser, including the pages you visit and other information that assists us in improving the Service. We collect and use this analytics information in aggregate form such that it cannot reasonably be manipulated to identify any particular individual user. 

##### Cookies information

When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets Credible help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use the Service (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on the Service), and allow us or our business partners to track your usage of the Service over time. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 

##### Log file information

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access the Service. When you use our Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. 

##### Clear gifs/web beacons information

When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our Users. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the Service. 

##### Commercial and marketing communications

We use the information we collect or receive to communicate directly with you. We may send you emails containing newsletters, promotions and special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you will be given the option to opt out or change your preferences. We also use your information to send you Service-related emails (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). You may not opt out of Service-related emails. 

##### Use of certain service type information we collect about you

We use or may use cookies, log file and clear gifs information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in and; (g) provide advertising to your browser. 

### Sharing of your information

We will not rent or sell your information to third parties outside Credible and its group companies (including any parent, subsidiaries and affiliates) without your consent, except as noted below: 

##### Who we may share your information with

We may share your information with Providers for the purpose of providing the Service to you such that they may provide you with information about Offers and other products and services they offer. If you sign up for a promotion, submit an Offer request, enroll in a service with a Provider, we may provide information that you have provided to us to Providers. Those Providers will be given limited access to your information as is reasonably necessary to deliver the Service. 

You agree that when you submit information to a Provider through the Service as a part of an Offer request, submission of your information to Providers may also be governed by Provider privacy and security policies which differ from the our Privacy Policy. It is your obligation to inquire as to the details of such policies from Providers directly. 

You understand that Providers may keep your information that relates to any Offer request that you may make through using the Service and any other information provided by Credible in the processing of any Offer request, whether or not you are qualified for an Offer from that Provider. You agree to notify any particular provider directly if you no longer want to them to keep your information. 

You agree that when you nominate a co-signer on an Offer request, that Credible may share Provider responses and/or Offers relating to your Offer request with your nominated co-signer. 

We may also share your information with other parties, such as third party service providers, who assist in completion of your information and/or verification of your identity. This may include (but is not limited to); credit bureaus, service providers that provide access to your existing accounts (at your request), your school, and other parties involved in the Offer request process. 

We also remind you that under our Terms of Use you authorize the use of your Account information to help complete Offer request forms. 

##### Who you may choose to share your User Content with

Any information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as User Content, becomes available to the public, as controlled by any applicable privacy settings. If you choose to set up a profile and you choose to change your privacy settings on the Service, please access your profile setting. Subject to your profile and privacy settings, any User Content that you make public is searchable by other Users. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information that you choose to submit in your User Content. 

##### What happens in the event of a change of control

We may buy or sell/divest/transfer Credible.com (including any shares in Credible), or any combination of its products, services, assets and/or businesses. Your information such as customer names and email addresses, User Content and other user information related to the Service may be among the items sold or otherwise transferred in these types of transactions. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcies, dissolutions, reorganizations, liquidations, similar transactions or proceedings involving all or a portion of the Credible. 

##### Instances where we are required to share your information

Credible will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Credible, our Users or others. 

##### Sharing certain service type information we collect about you

We may share certain service type information, including information obtained through tools such as cookies, log files, and clear gifs (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.): (i) with Providers for the purposes described in the section above on “How We Collect and Use Information.” We may also aggregate or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that aggregated, anonymized data with third parties. 

##### Ads on Credible

We may also share certain information such as your browser and cookie data and other data relating to your use of our Service with our business partners to deliver advertisements (“ads”) that may be of interest to you. Credible may allow third party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service. These third party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the ads and ad links that appear on the Service, and will automatically receive your IP address when they do so. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript and clear gifs, see above) to compile information about your browser’s visits and usage patterns on the Service, and to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize the advertising content. Credible does not sell, rent, or share the information we collect directly from you or about you from third parties with these third party ad servers or ad networks for such parties’ own marketing purposes. 

Please note that an advertiser may ask Credible to show an ad to a certain audience of Users (e.g., based on demographics or other interests). In that situation, Credible determines the target audience and Credible serves the advertising to that audience and only provides anonymous aggregated data to the advertiser. If you respond to such an ad, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. 

The Credible Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers or contact such advertisers for more information. 

### How we store and protect your information

##### Storage and processing

Your information collected through the Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Credible or its subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities. Credible may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which Credible or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy. 

##### Keeping your information safe

Credible cares about the security of your information, and uses commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through the Service. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Credible, at all times. However, Credible cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Credible or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed. Credible is not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party or Provider. 

No system can be completely secure. Although we take steps to secure your information, we provide no warranties, nor should you expect, that your information will always remain secure. Users should also take care with how they handle and disclose their information. Please refer to the Federal Trade Commission’s website for information about how to protect yourself against identity theft. The measures we take include: 

Web page security and encryption methods, including: 

  * Encryption of sensitive data. 
  * Public key cryptography algorithms with a minimum key size of 256 bits. 
  * Use of secure server communications in the form of HTTPS 
  * Transmission between your web server and our web server being protected using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology, which encrypts your information and makes it unreadable to anyone except Credible. You can verify this by checking for the key or lock icon on your browser. We use an Extended Validation SSL Certificate to give our users additional confidence 
  * Timeout Features to log you out if there has been no activity within a specified period of time 
  * The use of internal and external security and vulnerability testing techniques. 

##### Compromise of information

In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Credible will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations. 

### Your choices about your information

##### You control your account information and settings

If you choose to set up a profile, you may update your account information and email-communication preferences at any time by logging into your account and changing your profile settings. You can also stop receiving promotional email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe link” provided in such communications. We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests. As noted above, you may not opt out of Service-related communications (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, and technical and security notices). If you have any questions about reviewing or modifying your account information, you can contact us directly at [support@credible.com](mailto:support@credible.com). 

##### Opting out of collection of your information for Tracking / Advertising

Please refer to your browser’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. Note that disabling cookies and/or other tracking tools prevents Credible or its business partners from tracking your browser’s activities in relation to the Service, and for use in targeted advertising activities by third parties. However, doing so may disable many of the features available through the Service. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us directly at [support@credible.com](mailto:support@credible.com). 

##### How long we keep your User Content

Following termination or deactivation of your User account, Credible may retain your profile information and User Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes. In certain circumstances, we will be required by Federal and State regulations to store various information. In order to comply with those requirements, we may be unable to delete your information from our database until the expiration of the applicable period. 

### Children’s privacy

Credible does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Users. The Service and its content are not directed at children under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@credible.com](mailto:support@credible.com). 

### Links to other web sites and services

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Service or to which you direct Credible to retrieve information, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third party website or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. In addition, you agree that we are not responsible and we do not have control over any third parties that you authorize to access your User Content. If you are using a third party website or service and you allow such a third party access to your User Content you do so at your own risk. Credible is also not responsible for sites directing you to Credible. Our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy do not apply to those third party sites either. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources other than through the Service. 

### How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Service, please contact us at [support@credible.com](mailto:support@credible.com). 

### Changes to our privacy policy

Credible may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect the changes in our business and practices, and so you should review this page periodically. When we change the policy in a material manner we will update the ‘last modified’ date on this page. 

PLEASE PRINT AND RETAIN A COPY OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY FOR YOUR RECORDS.
